**LIMITED TIME OFFER: Receive a FREE Trial + up to 33% off on Select Plans!** Select Annual or Quarterly at checkout. Offer Ends 10/28/2024.

**LIMITED TIME OFFER: Receive a FREE Trial + up to 33% off on Select Plans!** Select Annual or Quarterly at checkout. Offer Ends 10/28/2024.

**LIMITED TIME OFFER: Receive a FREE Trial + up to 33% off on Select Plans!** Select Annual or Quarterly at checkout. Offer Ends 10/28/2024.

**LIMITED TIME OFFER: Receive a FREE Trial + up to 33% off on Select Plans!** Select Annual or Quarterly at checkout. Offer Ends 10/28/2024.

**LIMITED TIME OFFER: Receive a FREE Trial + up to 33% off on Select Plans!** Select Annual or Quarterly at checkout. Offer Ends 10/28/2024.

**LIMITED TIME OFFER: Receive a FREE Trial + up to 33% off on Select Plans!** Select Annual or Quarterly at checkout. Offer Ends 10/28/2024.

**LIMITED TIME OFFER: Receive a FREE Trial + up to 33% off on Select Plans!** Select Annual or Quarterly at checkout. Offer Ends 10/28/2024.

**LIMITED TIME OFFER: Receive a FREE Trial + up to 33% off on Select Plans!** Select Annual or Quarterly at checkout. Offer Ends 10/28/2024.

**LIMITED TIME OFFER: Receive a FREE Trial + up to 33% off on Select Plans!** Select Annual or Quarterly at checkout. Offer Ends 10/28/2024.

**LIMITED TIME OFFER: Receive a FREE Trial + up to 33% off on Select Plans!** Select Annual or Quarterly at checkout. Offer Ends 10/28/2024.

You updated your password.

**JavaScript seems to be disabled in your browser.** For the best experience on our site, be sure to turn on Javascript in your browser.

Enjoy this course and thousands of other programs with a Great Courses Plus membership

The Great Courses Plus is the premier service for people who love to learn. It gives you hundreds of great college-level courses from The Great Courses and series made for lifelong learners like you.

Enjoy Anywhere!

Already have an account?

Sign In

SHARE ON FACEBOOK

SHARE ON TWITTER

SHARE VIA EMAIL

    SUBJECTS

    FORMATS

*   Search Programs, Episodes, experts 

#### Sign In

Email

Password

 SHOW

 Remember me

Sign In

#### New To The Great Courses Plus?

Start your free trial to unlock over 18,000 lectures from the world’s greatest professors and experts on history, science, philosophy, religion, literature, health, travel, and more.

#### Reset Password

Enter the email address you used to create your account. We will email you instructions on how to reset your password.

Email

 Send Email

Forgot Your Email Address? [Contact Us](https://www.wondrium.com/contact)

#### If your email is in our system, a password reset email will be sent.

(Don't forget to check your junk email box!)

**Please do not attempt to reset your password again in the next 30 minutes.** This may cause issues with changing your password.

#### Reset Your Password

New Password

 SHOW

Confirm Password

 SHOW

Change Password

The Great Courses Plus Privacy Policy
=====================================

Welcome to The Great Courses Plus and to thegreatcoursesplus.com Website (“Website”).   The Teaching Company Sales, LLC d/b/a The Great Courses ("The Great Courses"), its subsidiaries and affiliates, or other members of our family of companies value your participation and loyalty. We are committed to the protection of subscriber, customer and community privacy. The Great Courses has created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate its commitment to the privacy and protection of your personal information. To better protect your privacy, The Great Courses provides this notice explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used in connection with our The Great Courses service.

By using the Website, you confirm that you accept our Terms and Conditions and our use of Cookies as set out in our [Cookies Policy](https://www.wondrium.com/cookies), and that you have read and understood this Privacy Notice.  We may amend this Privacy Notice at any time.  If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or disclose your Personal Information, we will post a notice on the Website and/or send an email to users who have provided an email address.

**Information about Us**

Our Service and Website is operated by The Teaching Company Sales, LLC, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, VA 20151-2299 (under the name of “The Great Courses”). If you would like information on how to contact us, click Contact Us.   “The Great Courses Plus” is the name of our subscription-based service.

**1\. What Information Is Collected**

The following are the types of information we may collect:

**Personal Information**

The Great Courses may collect personal information, which shall include but is not limited to, name, telephone number, email address, date of birth, home or business mailing address, and details regarding your mode of payment, _e.g._, credit/debit card or account information, when you access certain areas of the Website that require registration or payment for products and services, or if you require more information about those services.  
  
**Non-Personal Information**  
At other times, The Great Courses may collect information that cannot be used to directly identify you, such as browser type, Dynamic Internet Protocol (IP) address, “click stream” data, and similar non-personally identifiable information.  For example, we may aggregate non-personal information about you and other customers who visit certain areas of our Website. Aggregated information will not contain any information that can be linked directly back to you.  
  
While we take all reasonable steps to protect the privacy of our Website visitors, we cannot promise that the current limitations of our online applications programming will address every browser setting or honor every personal browser preference. In particular, we have not implemented the necessary program changes to honor “Do Not Track” or “DNT” browser signals. As our online applications programming is refined, we will take all reasonable steps to honor such requests in the future. Please return to this Privacy Policy for further updates on this topic.  
  
Further, our online service providers or business partners may implement technologies that allow for the collection of personally identifiable information over time and across Websites. We recommend that you review each privacy policy posted on the Websites that you visit to better understand privacy practices on those Websites.  
  
**Electronic Communications**  
When you open emails from us or engage in SMS or MMS communications, we may log and store such information. We may also keep records of various communications regarding the types of products and services that you indicate are of interest to you via your response to email and text messaging. You will always have the option to opt-out of such communications by clicking an “unsubscribe” link or replying “STOP” to our text messages.  
  
**  
2\. How Do We Collect Information**  
We may collect information from you in several different areas on the Website, including, without limitation, those described below:  
  
**Registration**  
You will be asked to complete a registration form and provide personally identifiable information.  You will be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to access your subscription, as well as to take advantage of certain features on the Website or digital messaging services, such as newsletters or contests. You will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to us and what communications you would like to receive; however, please be advised that many products and services available on the Website require registration and if you elect not to provide such information, you will not be able to take advantage of those products and services.  
  
**Contests or Sweepstakes**  
We periodically operate contests and sweepstakes through the Website and messaging services that will require registration or the submission of personal information. Your personally identifiable information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes (see the rules of each contest for details about how your personal information will be used, including postings to the Website).  
  
**Surveys and Games**  
From time-to-time we may request personally identifiable information from you in conjunction with a survey or games, such as quizzes. Participation is voluntary, and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. At times, you may have to register to vote or to take part in a survey. When you register to play games on our Website, you may be asked to provide personally identifiable information.  
  
**Cookies and Tracking Technology**  
We may use any number of tools to collect information about you, your computer access points, and the web browser that you use to connect to our Website. For example, “cookies” are tiny text files that we place on your computer’s hard drive when you visit our Website. We may use cookies to personalize your Website experience. You do not have to accept our cookies and you may delete them after they have been placed on your hard drive. If you do not accept or delete our cookies, some areas of our Website that you access may take more time to work, or may not function properly. For more information about cookies, visit: [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).  
  
The Great Courses may also collect additional information from your web browser each time you visit our Website. We may collect information on the pages that you visit, the promotions or advertisements that you click on, the courses you watch, and other actions that you take while using our Website. This information may include your IP address, the type of browser, the time that your browser was used to access our Website, and the referring Website address.  
  
Our Internet Service Providers (defined below) and supporting service platform providers may also use other standard web-based technologies to analyze your movements while accessing our Website. The technologies may include analytic solutions, web “beacons,” “pixel tags,” and “clear gifs.” These technologies help us ascertain the effectiveness of our product and service campaigns and marketing programs, allow us to customize the services offered on or through our Website, and help determine the best use for Website content, and product and service offerings. Some of this information, including the IP address, may be stored on our Internet service provider’s server logs, and may be available for extended periods of time.  
  
**Transaction Information**  
If you conduct a financial or other transaction with or on the Website, such as subscribe to The Great Courses or order other products/services offered on the Website, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain information from you, including contact information, demographic information, credit card and/or other financial information. Even though the collection form may have the look and feel of thegreatcoursesplus.com, please be aware you will be giving your information to our and your authorized payment processors (such as credit card service processors or Amazon Payments) and to third party Internet Service Providers, and that in some instances the Privacy Policies of those third party Internet Service Providers will govern the collection of your personal information. Please reference the privacy policies available from these pages for any privacy related concerns.  
  
We and/or our Internet Service Providers will use this information to complete the financial or other transaction that you have requested, _i.e.,_ to deliver the information, products or other services that you request or purchase, to invoice you, and in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy. For your protection, financial information is collected and stored through encrypted means.  
  
**3\. How Is your Information Used**  
The Great Courses and its partners may use your personal information and/or non-personally identifiable information for the following purposes:

* Provide you with The Great Courses products and services
* Communicate with you about your account or transactions with us and send you information about features on our Website and applications or changes to our policies
* Send you offers and promotions for The Great Courses products and services or third-party products and services 
* Personalize content and experiences on our Websites and applications
* Provide you with advertising based on your activity on our Websites and applications and on third-party sites and applications.
* Optimize or improve our products, services and operations
* Detect, investigate and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal

 The Great Courses uses the services of independent companies to provide certain services to you, including, without limitation, Website hosting services, course content distribution services, credit and debit card processing, mobile application providers, order fulfillment, contest and sweepstakes processing, and Internet connectivity services (“Internet Service Providers”) in connection with The Great Courses.  We may share your non-personal and personal information with these third parties as necessary to provide these services to you.  
  
We use your personal information to send you order confirmations. In such cases, you should receive via e-mail an order confirmation after placing your order.  You may also receive confirmation e-mails from your designated payment processor.  Occasionally, you will receive articles of interest on the subjects covered by our courses. From time-to-time you may receive e-mail surveys to vote for The Great Courses you want us to make, to rate the quality of The Great Courses Service or individual course titles, and to tell us what improvements to make to The Great Courses and our services. We may also use your personal information to notify you of special offers. You may receive e-mails notifying you when individual courses featured in our print catalogs and newsletters go on sale. These e-mails also make ordering extremely simple—if you see courses that interest you, simply click on the links in the e-mail to find out more.  
  
We may also use your IP address to help protect us and our Internet Service Providers from fraud. Additional uses of your non-personal and personal information will allow us to tailor products and services specific to your needs, to help organize and manage your customer relationship and our business, to conduct business, to provide you with customer and member support, to perform functions that are described to you at the time of collection, and to enforce our Website’s Terms of Use.  
  
We may also use non-personal aggregate information to improve our Website. For example, our Internet Service Providers may report to us that there were a particular number of visitors to a certain area of our Website, or that a certain number of men or a certain number of women completed our registration form in particular areas of our Website. Such information may also be used to analyze the effectiveness of our business and advertising models.  
  
**4\. Shared Information**  
We may share your personal information with the Internet Service Providers as appropriate.  We may also share personally identifiable information with outside, non-affiliated third parties that offer products and services that are complementary to our product lines. We may also disclose your personal information as is necessary to: (a) comply with a subpoena or court order; (b) cooperate with law enforcement or other government agency; (c) establish or exercise our legal rights; (d) protect the property or safety of our company and employees, contractors, vendors, and suppliers; (e) defend against legal claims; (f) help with internal and external investigations; or (g) as otherwise required by law or permitted by law. We may disclose your information in connection with the sale or merger of The Great Courses or any transaction that involves the sale or assignment of some or all of our assets.  
  
We use third-party ad serving, analytics, and audience and traffic measurement services.   We may use a third-party network advertiser to serve the advertisements on the Website or may use a traffic measurement service to analyze the traffic on the Website or the use of our Services. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to this Website and other Websites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products or Websites you might be interested in.  Audience and traffic measurement services allow us to collect anonymous traffic and behavior information from the Website by monitoring anonymous visitor activity. Although advertisers or other companies do not have access to the Website cookies, the Website's advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer if you choose to have your cookies enabled in your browser. Cookies allow third-party advertisers to show you advertisements or content you might be interested in. Note that any images (or any other parts of a web page) served by third parties in association with third-party cookies may serve as web beacons, which enable third parties to carry out the previously described activities. Other companies' uses of their cookies are subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Please visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout\_nonppii.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp) in order to learn more about the information collection practices and "opt-out" procedures of third-party ad servers we may use. We utilize the analysis services of Crazy Egg on our Website, click [here](https://www.crazyegg.com/privacy) to view its privacy policy and [here](https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out) to view its opt out feature. Additionally, Crazy Egg [terms and conditions](https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out) regarding your activity and content on this Website, its disclaimer of liability, arbitration and dispute resolution apply to this Website, and Crazy Egg is a third party beneficiary of such provisions.  
  
With regard to name and postal address only, from time to time, we may make our mailing list available to carefully screened companies. If you prefer we don’t share your name and postal address, please call our Customer Care team at 1-800-832-2412 or write to us at The Great Courses, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, VA, 20151-2299, Attn: Customer Care.  
  
**5\. Links To Third-party Websites**  
Links from this Website may allow you to directly access Websites operated by third parties, including, without limitation, our service providers or marketing partners. And, you may be able to access this Website or your The Great Courses subscription content through third parties with whom we have marketing relationships.  Some of these third-party marketing channels may be “co-branded” with our logo; however, note that  these third-party channels are not operated, controlled or maintained by The Great Courses. These channels or links are provided for your convenience only and should be used with your discretion and prudent judgment. Links from our Website to third-party Websites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement, or approval of the content, policies or practices of such third-party Websites. The collection and use of your information by such co-branding third parties is the responsibility of the co-branding partner, and they may use your personal information for their direct marketing purposes.  We are not responsible for any information these Websites or digital channels may obtain and we do not oversee their policies or practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information provided to or gathered by the third parties that operate them. The privacy policies of these third-party Websites may differ from ours. These Websites may ask you for Personal Information. Please review the privacy policy on third-party channels before submitting information, because we do not have control over the use of information collected on these Websites. Please review the privacy policies and practices of these digital channels before providing any Personal Information.  
  
**6\. Information Security**  
The Great Courses makes reasonable efforts to ensure that our Internet Service Providers have implemented physical, electronic, and procedural security measures to assist with safeguarding your personal information, and to help protect against unauthorized access and disclosure. Only our authorized personnel and our Internet Service Providers who perform legitimate business functions for The Great Courses are authorized to access your personal information.  
  
Notwithstanding our efforts, the Internet and online services have inherent security risks.  The Great Courses cannot promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information, personal searches, and other communications will always remain secure. You should take care with regard to how you handle and disclose your personal information or any username or password that you are required to use to access services on this Website or online service.  
  
**7\. Data Retention Periods**  
We will retain your personally identifiable information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.  
  
**8\. Other Social Media Websites, Blogs, Message Boards**  
The Website and The Great Courses Mobile applications may make chat rooms, forums, commenting and message boards available to you and other users. You are not required to provide any personal information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. If you post personal information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. In addition, when you post a comment, the user name with which you registered for the Website and your current location may be made publicly available on the Website and through The Great Courses Mobile applications. By using the commenting features of the Website and The Great Courses Mobile applications, you acknowledge that your user name and location information will be disclosed. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in these areas. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at: [contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.  
  
**9\. General Audience Website Not Directed Toward Children**  
This Website is a general audience Website. Our content is neither directed toward minors nor children who are under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If The Great Courses or our Internet Service Providers become aware that a minor or a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personal information without the parental consent, that information will be deleted from our databases. Parents who have questions about personal information that may have been submitted by a child under the age of 13 should email us at: [contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:ContactUs@TheGreatCoursesPlus.com)  
  
**10\. Consent to Privacy Policy**  
By using this Website or The Great Courses, you signify your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy. We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post a notice on the Website and/or send an email to users who have provided an email address. Please note that you should always update your personal information to provide us with a current email address.  
  
**11\. Access to Personal Information and Consent to Transfer**  
The first time that you provide us with registration information through our Website, you may be offered the opportunity to subscribe to and receive additional information about our products and services. After your first use, you can make changes to your personal information and your initial choices by accessing your account or by contacting customer service e-mail at [contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com).  
  
The United States may not have data privacy laws that are deemed to afford an equal level of protection for your Personal Information as those laws legislated at the direction of the European Union or similar geopolitical, national or regional legislative bodies. However, please be assured that The Great Courses will continue to adhere to the principles stated in this Privacy Policy and will make reasonable efforts to comply with applicable international, national, regional, territorial, and provincial laws in connection with any information collected through the Website. The Great Courses will endeavor to preserve the integrity, confidentiality, and security of personal information and afford such personal information reasonable level of protection.  
  
For those Website users located outside the United States, we advise you that your information may at times be accessible by individuals who are located worldwide including in countries that the European Commission or other geopolitical regions have not been determined to provide the same level of data protection as in your country, province, territory or geopolitical region. By providing us with your Personal Information, you consent to our use of it in accordance with The Great Courses Privacy Policy, including the transfer of your information across international boundaries to jurisdictions anywhere in the world as permitted by local law.  
  
**12\. Questions About This Privacy Policy**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the privacy practices of this Website, please contact us by email at [contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com).

**PRIVACY POLICY ADDENDUM FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS**

Under the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”), California residents are afforded certain rights regarding the personal information  The Great Courses (“we”, “our”, “us”) collect about them.  California residents may request any of the following: 

* The categories of information that we collected.
* The categories of sources from which the information is collected.
* The purpose for collecting information.
* The categories of third parties to whom we disclosed information, the categories of such information that was disclosed (if applicable), and the purpose for disclosing information.
* The specific pieces of information we collected.

You may also request the deletion of information we have collected, as well as the right to opt-out of the sale of your personal information. 

Consistent with the California Consumer Protection Act, we will consider and timely process data access and deletion requests. We will not unlawfully discriminate against you for making any such requests.  To initiate access or deletion requests, you can contact us at [Calprivacy@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:Calprivacy@thegreatcoursesplus.com).

**SALES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We allow companies to use cookies and other tracking technologies on our sites that allow those companies to collect information about your website activity and use that information to target advertisements to you online.  You can exercise control over the use of these technologies.  _See_ the [Cookies Policy](https://www.wondrium.com/cookies)**.**  In addition, to opt-out of the “sale” of personal information, you can click here:  [Do Not Sell My Personal Information](https://www.wondrium.com/ccpa).

**HOW WE COLLECT AND SHARE CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS’ INFORMATION**

Over the last 12 months, personal information we have collected and shared includes the following:

| Categories of Information | Sources of Information | Uses of Information | Sharing of Information |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Identifiers, including name, telephone number, email address, birthdate, home or business mailing address, IP address, demographic information credit card and account information, and username and password if you register. | We collect this information directly from you when you register, complete surveys, enter contests or sweepstakes, transact business with us, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and automatically when you visit the Website, and  from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To confirm purchases, deliver products and services, determine your location, communicate with you, send articles of interest to you, send email surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services or third parties’ products and services, improve our products and services, detect and investigate incidents and protect against fraud, analysis of the Website traffic. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfilment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Personal information as defined by Cal. Civ. Code 1798.80, including name, telephone number, email address, birthdate, home or business mailing address, IP address, demographic information credit card and account information, and username and password if you register. | We collect this information directly from you when you register, complete surveys, enter contests or sweepstakes, transact business with us, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and automatically when you visit the Website, and  from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To confirm purchases, deliver products and services, determine your location, communicate with you, send articles of interest to you, send email surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services or third parties’ products and services, improve our products and services, detect and investigate incidents and protect against fraud, analysis of the Website traffic. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfilment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Characteristics of protected classifications, including race, color, religion/creed, national origin or ancestry, sex, gender, age, physical/mental disability, veteran status, genetic information, citizenship, occupation, marital status, income and/or employment status. | We may collect this information directly from you when you complete surveys or register for information, products and services. | To market, sell, and improve our products and services, send you surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services, send articles of interest to you. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfilment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Commercial information including information on your purchases, mode of payment (e.g. credit/debit card purchases), products and services you show interest in, your marketing preferences, survey responses, electronic communications. | We collect this information directly from you when you register, complete surveys, enter contests or sweepstakes, transact business with us, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and automatically when you visit the Website, and  from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To confirm purchases, deliver products and services, determine your location, communicate with you, send articles of interest to you, send email surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services or third parties’ products and services, improve our products and services, detect and investigate incidents and protect against fraud, analysis of the Website traffic. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfilment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Internet or other electronic network activity information including, information about your visit, including information collected through the use of cookies, website  pages visited, “click stream” data, promotions you click on, courses watched, your Website movement, and other actions you take while using our Website, technical information, browser type, the time that your browser was used to access our Website, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and the referring website address. | We collect this information directly from you when you register, complete surveys, enter contests or sweepstakes, transact business with us, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and automatically when you visit the Website, and  from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To confirm purchases, deliver products and services, determine your location, communicate with you, send articles of interest to you, send email surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services or third parties’ products and services, improve our products and services, detect and investigate incidents and protect against fraud, analysis of the Website traffic | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfillment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory or similar information, including your customer support calls (which may be recorded for training purposes). | We collect this information directly from you when you register, transact business with us,, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and automatically when you visit the Website, and  from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To confirm purchases, deliver products and services, determine your location, communicate with you, send articles of interest to you, send email surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services or third parties’ products and services, improve our products and services, detect and investigate incidents and protect against fraud, analysis of the Website traffic. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfillment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Professional and employment related information such as your occupation, and/or your professional status. | We collect this information directly from you when you register, complete surveys, enter contests or sweepstakes, transact business with us, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To market, sell, and improve our products and services, send you surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services, send articles of interest to you. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfillment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Educational information, such as education level attained, degrees attained, and schools attended, may be collected. | We collect this information directly from you when you complete surveys, or enter contests or sweepstakes, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To market, sell, and improve our products and services, send you surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services, send articles of interest to you. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfillment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Inferences derived from personal information, including your purchasing habits and patterns, your purchasing and product preferences. | This information is derived from categories of information collected. | To market, sell, and improve our products and services, send you surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services, send articles of interest to you. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfillment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |

**Effective Date: November 1, 2019 - US, Revised January 1, 2020, Revised June 8, 2021, Revised May 5, 2022, Revised June 4, 2024**

Welcome to The Great Courses Plus and to the thegreatcoursesplus.com website (“Website”).   The Teaching Company Sales, LLC d/b/a The Great Courses (“The Great Courses”, the "Company", "we" and "us"), its subsidiaries and affiliates value your participation and loyalty. We are committed to the protection of subscriber and customer privacy. The Great Courses has created this Privacy Notice in order to demonstrate its commitment to the privacy and protection of your Personal Information (as defined below). To better protect your privacy, The Great Courses provides this notice explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used in connection with our  The Great Courses Plus service.

By using the Website, you confirm that you accept our Terms and Conditions and our use of Cookies as set out in our Cookies Policy, and that you have read and understood this Privacy Notice.  We may amend this Privacy Notice at any time.  If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or disclose your Personal Information, we will post a notice on the Website and/or send an email to users who have provided an email address.

**Information About Us**

Our service and Website are operated by The Teaching Company Sales, LLC, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, VA 20151-2299 (under the name of “The Great Courses”). [Click here](https://www.thegreatcoursesplus.com/contact-us) if you would like more information on how to contact us.  “The Great Courses Plus” is the name of our subscription-based service.

**Privacy Officer**

Our Company Privacy Officer is our General Counsel, who can be reached at The Teaching Company Sales, LLC, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, Virginia 20151, Attn: General Counsel.  Our Privacy Officer can also be reached at [legal@teachco](mailto:legal@teachco).com.

**1\. What Information Is Collected**

The following are the types of information we may collect:

**Personal Information**

The Great Courses may collect personal information (“Personal Information”), which includes any information relating to you or which can be used to identify you. This shall include but is not limited to, name, telephone number, email address, date of birth, home or business mailing address, IP address, and details regarding your mode of payment (_e.g._, credit/debit card or account information).

**Non-Personal Information**

At other times, The Great Courses may collect information that cannot be used to directly identify you (“Non-Personal Information” and, together with Personal Information, “Information”), such as browser type or “click stream” data. We may aggregate Non-Personal Information about you and other customers who visit certain areas of our Website. Aggregated information will not contain any information that can be linked directly back to you. If certain Non-Personal Information could identify you, when combined with the Personal Information you have given us, this will be considered Personal Information for the purposes of this Privacy Notice.

**Electronic Communications**

When you engage in email, SMS or MMS communications, we may log and store such information, as necessary, or for training and monitoring purposes.

We may also keep records of various communications regarding the types of products and services that you indicate are of interest to you via your response to email and text messaging.

You have the option to opt-out of our marketing communications when you complete your subscription check out process on the Website or by clicking “unsubscribe” in our emails or replying “STOP” to our text messages.

While we take all reasonable steps to protect the privacy of our Website visitors, we cannot promise that the current limitations of our online applications programming will address every browser setting or honor every personal browser preference. In particular, we have not implemented the necessary program changes to honor “Do Not Track” or “DNT” browser signals. As our online applications programming is refined, we will take all reasonable steps to honor such requests in the future. Please return to this Privacy Notice for further updates on this topic.

Our online service providers or business partners may implement technologies that allow for the collection of personally identifiable information over time and across third party websites. We recommend that you review each privacy policy posted on the websites that you visit to better understand privacy practices on those websites.

**2\. How Do We Collect Information**

We may collect Information from you in several different areas on the Website, including, without limitation, those described below:

**Registration**

You will be asked to complete a registration form and provide Personal Information.  You will be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to access your subscription, as well as to take advantage of certain features on the Website or digital messaging services. You will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose Personal Information to us and what communications you would like to receive. Please be advised that access to certain products and services available on the Website require registration and if you elect not to provide such information, you will not be able to take advantage of those products and services.

**Contests Or Sweepstakes**

We may operate contests and sweepstakes through the Website and messaging services connected to contests and sweepstakes that will require registration or the submission of Personal Information. This Personal Information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes (see the rules of each contest for details about how your Personal Information will be used, including postings to the Website).

**Surveys And Games**

From time-to-time we may request Personal Information from you in conjunction with a survey or games, such as quizzes. Participation is voluntary, and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose Personal Information to the Website. At times, you may have to register to vote or to take part in a survey. When you register to play games on our Website, you may be asked to provide Personal Information.

**Transaction Information**

If you conduct a financial transaction on the Website, such as subscribing to The Great Courses Plus service or order other products/services offered on the Website, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain Personal Information from you, including contact information, demographic information, credit card and other financial information. Even though the collection form may have the look and feel of thegreatcoursesplus.com, please be aware you will be giving your Personal Information to our authorized payment processors (such as credit card service processors) and to third party Internet Service Providers, and that in some instances the Privacy Policies of those third-party Internet Service Providers will govern the collection of your Personal Information. Please reference the privacy policies of such third parties, as directed, for any privacy related concerns.

**Contacting Customer Care**

If you contact us by email, telephone or any other means to report a problem with the Website or our services, or you request information from us, we may record your Personal Information, as well as the content of your communication, for account management, training and monitoring purposes.  Calls may be recorded for training and monitoring purposes.

**Cookies and Tracking Technology**

We may use any number of tools to collect Personal Information about you, your computer access points, and the web browser that you use to connect to our Website. For example, “cookies” are tiny text files that we place on your computer’s hard drive when you visit our Website. We may use cookies as detailed in our [Cookies Policy](https://www.wondrium.com/cookies) to personalize your Website experience and improve our services.

The Great Courses may also collect additional Information from your web browser each time you visit our Website. This information may be anonymized/aggregated (Non-Personal Information) or may identify you when combined with the Personal Information you have given us. This information will include:

* Information about your visit, including the pages that you visit, “click stream” data to, through and from the Website (including date and time), products you viewed and searched for, length of visits to certain pages including video content, page response times, download errors, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), the promotions or advertisements that you click on, the courses you watch, and other actions that you take while using our Website; and
* Technical Information, including your login information, your IP address, the type of browser, the time that your browser was used to access our Website, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and the referring website address.

Our Internet Service Providers (defined below) and supporting service platform providers may also use other standard web-based technologies to analyze your movements while accessing our Website. The technologies may include analytic solutions, web “beacons,” “pixel tags,” and “clear gifs.” These technologies help us ascertain the effectiveness of our product and service campaigns and marketing programs, allow us to customize the services offered on or through our Website, and help determine the best use for Website content, and product and service offerings. Some of this information, including the IP address, may be stored on our Internet Service Provider’s server logs, and may be available for extended periods of time. Please see our Cookies Policy for further details.

**3\. How Your Information Is Used**

The Great Courses and its partners may use or disclose your Personal Information and/or Non-Personal Information for the following purposes:

* Confirm and enable your subscription;
* Carry out obligations arising from any contract entered into between you and us and to provide you with information, products and services;
* Determine your general geographic location and internet service provider to enable us to quickly and efficiently respond to inquiries and requests;
* Complete financial or other transactions that you have requested;
* Communicate with you about your account or transactions with us, including order confirmation from us or your designated payment processor;
* Send you information regarding changes to our policies;

* Personalize content and experiences on our Websites;
* Provide you with advertising based on your activity on our Websites and applications and on third party sites and applications;
* Send you articles of interest on the subjects covered by our courses;
* Send you e-mail surveys to vote for the courses you want us to make, to rate the quality of our service or individual course titles, and to tell us what improvements to make to our services;

* Optimize or improve our products, services and operations;
* Detect, investigate and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal and

* Send you offers and promotions for The Great Courses products and services, or third-party products and services if you have specifically consented to this.

We may also use your IP address to help protect us and our Internet Service Providers from fraud. Additional uses of your Non-Personal and Personal Information will allow us to tailor products and services specific to your needs, to help organize and manage your customer relationship and our business, to conduct business, to provide you with customer and member support, to perform functions that are described to you at the time of collection, and to enforce our Website’s Terms of Use.

We may also use Non-Personal aggregate information to improve our Website. For example, our Internet Service Providers may report to us that there were a particular number of visitors to a certain area of our Website, or that a certain number of men or a certain number of women completed our registration form in particular areas of our Website. Such information may also be used to analyze the effectiveness of our business and advertising models.

**4\. Shared Information**

The Great Courses uses the services of independent companies to provide certain services to you, including, without limitation, website hosting services, cloud hosting service providers (such as Amazon Web Services), course content distribution services, credit and debit card processing, mobile application providers, order fulfilment, contest and sweepstakes processing, and internet connectivity services (“Internet Service Providers”) in connection with The Great Courses.  We may share your Non-Personal and Personal Information with these third parties to the extent necessary to carry out obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.

We may work with Facebook, other social network sites, on-line marketing platforms and programmatic advertising services to display interest-based TTC ads to you in various on-line settings. We may share hashed/encrypted email addresses or phone numbers with these social media and on-line platforms to enable them to identify which users use our service.  If you do not want to receive interest-based ads on these sites, you can adjust your ad preferences through your settings on those sites.

We may also disclose your Personal Information as is necessary to:

1. comply with a subpoena or court order;
2. cooperate with law enforcement or other government agencies;
3. establish or exercise our legal rights;
4. protect the property or safety of our company and employees, contractors, vendors, and suppliers;
5. defend against legal claims;
6. help with internal and external investigations; or
7. as otherwise required by law or permitted by law.

We may disclose your information in connection with the sale or merger of The Great Courses or any transaction that involves the sale or assignment of some or all of our assets.

With your consent we use third-party ad serving, analytics, and audience and traffic measurement services.   We may use a third-party network advertiser to serve the advertisements on the Website or may use a traffic measurement service to analyze the traffic on the Website or the use of our Services. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to this Website and other Websites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products or Websites you might be interested in.  Audience and traffic measurement services allow us to collect anonymous traffic and behavior information from the Website by monitoring anonymous visitor activity. The Website's advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer with your consent. Cookies allow third-party advertisers to show you advertisements or content you might be interested in with your consent. Note that any images (or any other parts of a web page) served by third parties in association with third-party cookies may serve as web beacons, which enable third parties to carry out the previously described activities with your consent. Please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.wondrium.com/cookies) for further details.  

With regard to name and postal address only, from time to time and if you have given consent, we may make our mailing list available to carefully screened companies. You have the option to withhold your consent when you complete your registration on the Website.  Thereafter, if you would like to withdraw your consent, please contacting us at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com), or write to us at The Great Courses, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, VA, 20151-2299, Attn: Customer Care or by contacting the third party who has contacted you.

**5\. Links To Third-party Websites**

Links from this Website may allow you to directly access websites operated by third parties, including, without limitation, our service providers or marketing partners. The privacy policies of these third-party websites may differ from ours. These websites may ask you for Personal Information. Please review the privacy policy on third-party websites before submitting information, because we do not have control over the use of information collected on these websites.  

You may be able to access this Website or your The Great Courses Plus subscription content through third parties with whom we have marketing relationships.  Some of these third-party marketing channels may be “co-branded” with our logo; however, note that these third-party channels are not operated, controlled or maintained by The Great Courses. These channels or links are provided for your convenience only and should be used with your discretion and prudent judgment. Links from our Website to third-party websites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement, or approval of the content, policies or practices of such third-party websites. The collection and use of your information by such co-branded third party is the responsibility of the co-branding partner, and they may use your personal information for their direct marketing purposes.  We are not responsible for any information these websites or digital channels may obtain and we do not oversee their policies or practices. This Privacy Notice does not apply to information provided to or gathered by the third parties that operate them.

**6\. Information Security And Storage**

**Australian subscribers:** Information we collect about you is likely to be transferred to, stored at, or disclosed outside Australia, including to the United States. It may also be processed by staff operating outside Australia who work for us or a third party. This includes staff engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services as listed elsewhere in this Privacy Notice. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your Information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Notice. 

The Great Courses makes reasonable efforts to ensure that our Internet Service Providers, and any other person to whom we disclose your Personal Information to, have implemented appropriate physical, electronic, and procedural security measures to assist with safeguarding your Personal Information, and to help protect against unauthorized access and disclosure. We use contracts and other measures with our service providers to maintain the confidentiality and security of your Personal Information and to prevent such Personal Information from being used for any other purpose.        

Notwithstanding our efforts, the Internet and online services have inherent security risks. The Great Courses cannot promise, and you should not expect, that your Personal Information, personal searches, and other communications will always remain secure. You should take care with regard to how you handle and disclose your Personal Information or any username or password that you are required to use to access services on the Website or online service.

We store your Personal Information electronically in secure servers located in the United States

**7\.  Deleting The Information We Hold About You**

We will retain your Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. You have the right to cancel your account or to request that we delete (or restrict the use of) any, or all, of the Information we hold about you, unless we need to retain your Information as necessary e.g. in order to comply with our legal obligations, comply with audit requirements, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. If you would like us to delete your Information, please contact us at [ContactUs@thegreatcouresplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com).

We may restrict or block the processing of your request to delete Information in the following circumstances:

1. where you have made a request that your Information be deleted or you have questioned the accuracy of your Information, and your request is being verified; or
2. where we need to retain the data to comply with law, regulation, internal audit requirements, or to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim.

**8\. Accessing Your Information**

You have the right to know what Information we hold about you and its source, the categories of the Information, whether it is shared with third parties, whether it has been sent outside Australia, and if so what safeguards are in place, how we use your Information, the purpose of that use and, where possible, the period for which your Information will be stored.

You are entitled to a copy of all the Information we hold on you.  This request should be made to [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com). We will respond to the extent reasonably possible and in accordance with applicable law.

**9\.  Your Right to Rectification**

We take care to keep Personal Information in our records as accurate, complete and up to date as necessary for the purposes for which it is used. However, we also rely on you to tell us when your Personal Information changes. If you believe we hold inaccurate or incomplete Information about you, or would like us to delete it from our records, please contact us at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com).

**10\. Other Social Media Websites, Blogs, Message Boards**

The Website and The Great Courses Plus Mobile applications may make chat rooms, forums, commenting and message boards available to you and other users. You are not required to provide any Personal Information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. If you post Personal Information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. In addition, when you post a comment, the user name with which you registered for the Website and your current location may be made publicly available on the Website and through The Great Courses Plus Mobile applications. By using the commenting features of the Website and The Great Courses Plus Mobile applications, you acknowledge that your user name and location information will be disclosed. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose Personal Information in these areas. To request removal of your Personal Information from our message boards or other community forums, contact us at: [ContactUs@thegreatcouresplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**11\.  General Audience Website Not Directed Toward Children**

This Website is a general audience Website. Our content is neither directed toward minors nor children who are under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If The Great Courses or our Internet Service Providers become aware that a minor or a child under the age of 13 has provided us with Personal Information without the parental consent, that information will be deleted from our databases. Parents who have questions about Personal Information that may have been submitted by a child under the age of 13 should email us at: [](mailto:ContactUs@TheGreatCoursesPlus.com)[ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:ContactUs@TheGreatCoursesPlus.com)

**12\.  Consent to Privacy Notice**

By using this Website or The Great Courses Plus Service, you signify that you have read and agree with the terms of this Privacy Notice. When you register with The Great Courses Plus, you will be asked to consent to certain uses of your Personal Information. You have the right to withdraw this consent at any time by contacting us at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:Contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com). We may amend this Privacy Notice at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your Personal Information, we will post a notice on the Website and/or send an email to users who have provided an email address. Please note that you should always update your Personal Information and provide us with a current email address. 

**13\.  Australian subscribers: complaints about a breach of privacy**

**For Australian subscribers:** If you believe that we have not complied with this Privacy Policy or the Australian Privacy Principles, please contact us at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:Contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com).  We will investigate the complaint and determine whether a breach has occurred and what action, if any, to take.  When contacting us, please provide as much detail as possible in relation to the query, issue or complaint.

We will take any privacy complaint seriously.  We will aim to resolve any such complaint in a timely and efficient manner.  We request that you cooperate with us during this process and provide us with relevant information we may require.

We expect our procedures will deal fairly and promptly with your complaint. However, if you remain dissatisfied, you can also make a formal complaint with the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (which is the regulator responsible for privacy in Australia): 

**Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC)**

Complaints must be made in writing.

| Phone | Mail | Website |
| --- | --- | --- |
| 1300 363 992 | Director of Compliance Office of the Australian Information Commissioner GPO Box 5218 Sydney NSW 2001 | [www.oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/) |

**14\. Questions About This Privacy Notice**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice or the privacy practices of this Website, please contact us by email at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com).

You may also send a letter to:

The Great Courses

Attn: Customer Care    

4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400

Chantilly, VA USA 20151-2299

**Effective Date:  October 2017, Revised June 8, 2021, Revised June 4, 2024**

Welcome to The Great Courses and to the thegreatcoursesplus.com website (“Website”).   The Teaching Company Sales, LLC d/b/a The Great Courses (“The Great Courses”, the "Company", "we" and "us"), its subsidiaries and affiliates value your participation and loyalty. We are committed to the protection of subscriber and customer privacy. The Great Courses has created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate its commitment to the privacy and protection of your personal information. To better protect your privacy, The Great Courses provides this notice explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used in connection with our The Great Courses Plus service.

By using the Website, you confirm that you accept our Terms and Conditions and our use of Cookies as set out in our [Cookies Policy](https://www.wondrium.com/cookies), and that you have read and understood this Privacy Notice.  We may amend this Privacy Notice at any time.  If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or disclose your Personal Information, we will post a notice on the Website and/or send an email to users who have provided an email address.

 **Information about Us**

Our Service and Website is operated by The Teaching Company Sales, LLC, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, VA 20151-2299 (under the name of “The Great Courses”). [Click here](https://www.wondrium.com/contact-us) if you would like more information on how to contact us. “The Great Courses Plus” is the name of our subscription-based service.

**Privacy Officer**

Our Company Privacy Officer is our General Counsel, who can be reached at The Teaching Company Sales, LLC, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, Virginia 20151, Attn: General Counsel.  Our Privacy Officer can also be reached at [legal@teachco.com](mailto:legal@teachco.com)

**1\.  What Information Is Collected**

The following are the types of information we may collect:

**Personal Information**

The Great Courses may collect personal information (“Personal Information”), which shall include but is not limited to, name, telephone number, email address, date of birth, home or business mailing address, and details regarding your mode of payment (_e.g._, credit/debit card or account information) when you access certain areas of the Website that require registration or payment for products and services, or if you require more information about those services.

**Non-Personal Information**

At other times, The Great Courses may collect information that cannot be used to directly identify you (“Non-Personal Information” and together with Personal Information, “Information”), such as browser type, Dynamic Internet Protocol (IP) address, “click stream” data, and similar non-personally identifiable information.  For example, we may aggregate Non-Personal Information about you and other customers who visit certain areas of our Website. Aggregated information will not contain any information that can be linked directly back to you.

**Electronic Communications**

When you engage in email, SMS, or MMS communications, we may log and store such information. We may also keep records of various communications regarding the types of products and services that you indicate are of interest to you via your response to email and text messaging. You will always have the option to opt-out of such communications by clicking the “unsubscribe” link in your “Your Account” section.

You have the option to opt-out of our marketing communications when you complete your subscription check out process on the Website or by clicking "unsubscribe" in our emails or replying "STOP" to our text messages.

While we take all reasonable steps to protect the privacy of our Website visitors, we cannot promise that the current limitations of our online applications programming will address every browser setting or honor every personal browser preference. In particular, we have not implemented the necessary program changes to honor “Do Not Track” or “DNT” browser signals. As our online applications programming is refined, we will take all reasonable steps to honor such requests in the future. Please return to this Privacy Policy for further updates on this topic.

Our online service providers or business partners may implement technologies that allow for the collection of personally identifiable information over time and across third party websites. We recommend that you review each privacy policy posted on the websites that you visit to better understand privacy practices on those websites.

**2\.  How Do We Collect Information**

We may collect Information from you in several different areas on the Website, including, without limitation, those described below:

**Registration**

You will be asked to complete a registration form and provide Personal Information.  You will be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to access your subscription, as well as to take advantage of certain features on the Website or digital messaging services, such as newsletters, email or contests. You will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose Personal Information to us and what communications you would like to receive; however, please be advised that many products and services available on the Website require registration and if you elect not to provide such information, you will not be able to take advantage of those products and services.

**Contests Or Sweepstakes**

We may periodically operate contests and sweepstakes through the Website and messaging services that will require registration or the submission of Personal Information. This Information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes (see the rules of each contest for details about how your Personal Information will be used, including postings to the Website).

**Surveys And Games**

From time-to-time we may request Personal Information from you in conjunction with a survey or games, such as quizzes. Participation is voluntary, and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose Personal Information to the Website. At times, you may have to register to vote or to take part in a survey. When you register to play games on our Website, you may be asked to provide Personal Information.

**Transaction Information**

If you conduct a financial transaction on the Website, such as subscribing to The Great Courses Plus or order other products/services offered on the Website, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain Personal Information from you, including contact information, demographic information, credit card and other financial information. Even though the collection form may have the look and feel of thegreatcoursesplus.com, please be aware you will be giving your Personal Information to our and your authorized payment processors (such as credit card service processors) and to third party Internet Service Providers, and that in some instances the Privacy Policies of those third party Internet Service Providers will govern the collection of your Personal Information. Please reference the privacy policies of such third-parties, for any privacy related concerns.

**Cookies and Tracking Technology**

We may use any number of tools to collect Non-Personal Information about you, your computer access points, and the web browser that you use to connect to our Website. For example, “cookies” are tiny text files that we place on your computer’s hard drive when you visit our Website. We may use cookies to personalize your Website experience. You do not have to accept our cookies and you may delete them after they have been placed on your hard drive. If you do not accept or delete our cookies, some areas of our Website that you access may take more time to work, or may not function properly. For more information about cookies, visit: http://www.allaboutcookies.org.

The Great Courses may also collect additional Non-Personal Information from your web browser each time you visit our Website. We may collect Information on the pages that you visit, the promotions or advertisements that you click on, the courses you watch, and other actions that you take while using our Website. This information may include your IP address, the type of browser, the time that your browser was used to access our Website, and the referring Website address.

Our Internet Service Providers (defined below) and supporting service platform providers may also use other standard web-based technologies to analyze your movements while accessing our Website. The technologies may include analytic solutions, web “beacons,” “pixel tags,” and “clear gifs.” These technologies help us ascertain the effectiveness of our product and service campaigns and marketing programs, allow us to customize the services offered on or through our Website, and help determine the best use for Website content, and product and service offerings. Some of this information, including the IP address, may be stored on our Internet service provider’s server logs, and may be available for extended periods of time.

**3\. How Your Information Is Used**

The Great Courses and its partners may use your Personal Information and/or Non-Personal Information for the following purposes:

* Confirm and enable your subscription;
* Carry out obligations arising from any contract entered into between you and us and to provide you with information, products and services;
* Determine your general geographic location and internet service provider to enable us to quickly and efficiently respond to inquiries and requests;
* Complete financial or other transactions that you have requested;
* Communicate with you about your account or transactions with us, including order confirmation from us or your designated payment processor;
* Send you information regarding changes to our policies;

* Personalize content and experiences on our Websites;
* Provide you with advertising based on your activity on our Websites and applications and on third party sites and applications;
* Send you articles of interest on the subjects covered by our courses;
* Send you e-mail surveys to vote for the courses you want us to make, to rate the quality of our service or individual course titles, and to tell us what improvements to make to our services;

* Optimize or improve our products, services and operations;
* Detect, investigate and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal and

* Send you offers and promotions for The Great Courses products and services, or third-party products and services.

The Great Courses uses the services of independent companies to provide certain services to you, including, without limitation, Website hosting services, course content distribution services, credit and debit card processing, mobile application providers, order fulfilment, and Internet connectivity services (“Internet Service Providers”) in connection with The Great Courses.  We may share your Non-Personal and Personal Information with these third parties as necessary to provide these services to you.

We use your Personal Information to send you order confirmations. In such cases, you should receive via e-mail an order confirmation after placing your order.  You may also receive confirmation e-mails from your designated payment processor.  Occasionally, you will receive articles of interest on the subjects covered by our Service or courses. From time-to-time you may receive e-mail surveys to vote for The Great Courses you want us to make, to rate the quality of The Great Courses Plus Service or individual course titles, and to tell us what improvements to make to The Great Courses Plus and our Services. We may also use your Personal Information to notify you of special offers. You may receive e-mails notifying you when individual courses featured in our The Great Courses print catalogs and web site go on sale. These e-mails also make ordering extremely simple—if you see courses that interest you, simply click on the links in the e-mail to find out more.

We may also use your IP address to help protect us and our Internet Service Providers from fraud. Additional uses of your Non-Personal and Personal Information will allow us to tailor products and services specific to your needs, to help organize and manage your customer relationship and our business, to conduct business, to provide you with customer and member support, to perform functions that are described to you at the time of collection, and to enforce our Website’s Terms of Use.

We may also use Non-Personal aggregate information to improve our Website. For example, our Internet Service Providers may report to us that there were a particular number of visitors to a certain area of our Website, or that a certain number of men or a certain number of women completed our registration form in particular areas of our Website. Such information may also be used to analyze the effectiveness of our business and advertising models.

**4\. Shared Information**

The Great Courses uses the services of independent companies to provide certain services to you, including, without limitation, website hosting services, cloud hosting service providers (such as Amazon Web Services), course content distribution services, credit and debit card processing, mobile application providers, order fulfilment, contest and sweepstakes processing, and internet connectivity services (“Internet Service Providers”) in connection with The Great Courses.  We may share your Non-Personal and Personal Information with these third parties to the extent necessary to carry out obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.

We may work with Facebook, other social network sites, on-line marketing platforms and programmatic advertising services to display interest-based TTC ads to you in various on-line settings. We may share hashed/encrypted email addresses or phone numbers with these social media and on-line platforms to enable them to identify which users use our service.  If you do not want to receive interest-based ads on these sites, you can adjust your ad preferences through your settings on those sites.

We may also disclose your Personal Information as is necessary to:

1. comply with a subpoena or court order;
2. cooperate with law enforcement or other government agencies;
3. establish or exercise our legal rights;
4. protect the property or safety of our company and employees, contractors, vendors, and suppliers;
5. defend against legal claims;
6. help with internal and external investigations; or
7. as otherwise required by law or permitted by law.

We may disclose your information in connection with the sale or merger of The Great Courses or any transaction that involves the sale or assignment of some or all of our assets.

With your consent we use third-party ad serving, analytics, and audience and traffic measurement services.   We may use a third-party network advertiser to serve the advertisements on the Website or may use a traffic measurement service to analyze the traffic on the Website or the use of our Services. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to this Website and other Websites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products or Websites you might be interested in.  Audience and traffic measurement services allow us to collect anonymous traffic and behavior information from the Website by monitoring anonymous visitor activity. The Website's advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer with your consent. Cookies allow third-party advertisers to show you advertisements or content you might be interested in with your consent. Note that any images (or any other parts of a web page) served by third parties in association with third-party cookies may serve as web beacons, which enable third parties to carry out the previously described activities with your consent. Please see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.wondrium.com/cookies) for further details.  

With regard to name and postal address only, from time to time and if you have given consent, we may make our mailing list available to carefully screened companies. If you would like to withdraw your consent, please contacting us at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com), or write to us at The Great Courses, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, VA, 20151-2299, Attn: Customer Care or by contacting the third party who has contacted you.

**5\. Links To Third-party Websites**

Links from this Website may allow you to directly access websites operated by third parties, including, without limitation, our service providers or marketing partners. The privacy policies of these third-party websites may differ from ours. These websites may ask you for Personal Information. Please review the privacy policy on third-party websites before submitting information, because we do not have control over the use of information collected on these websites.

You may be able to access this Website or your The Great Courses Plus subscription content through third parties, including App providers, with whom we have marketing relationships.  Some of these third-party marketing channels may be “co-branded” with our logo; however, note that these third-party channels are not operated, controlled or maintained by The Great Courses. These channels or links are provided for your convenience only and should be used with your discretion and prudent judgment. Links from our Website to third-party websites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement, or approval of the content, policies or practices of such third-party websites. The collection and use of your information by such third parties is the responsibility of the third parties, and they may use your personal information as described in their own privacy policies and terms of use.  We are not responsible for any information these Websites, Apps or digital channels may obtain and we do not oversee their policies or practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information provided to or gathered by the third parties that operate them. The privacy policies of these third-party Websites and Apps may differ from ours. These Websites and Apps may ask you for Personal Information. Please review the privacy policy on third-party channels before submitting information, because we do not have control over the use of information collected on these Websites or Apps.

**6\. Information Security**

The Great Courses makes reasonable efforts to ensure that our Internet Service Providers and any other person to whom we disclose your Personal Information to have implemented appropriate physical, electronic, and procedural security measures to assist with safeguarding your Personal Information, and to help protect against unauthorized access and disclosure. We use contracts and other measures with our service providers to maintain the confidentiality and security of your Personal Information and to prevent such Personal Information from being used for any other purpose. 

Our Internet Service Providers and other persons to whom we disclose Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, may perform activities outside of Canada. As a result, your Personal Information may be used, stored and/or accessed in countries outside of Canada, including without limitation the United States. However, all such Personal Information will be protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Please note that when your Personal Information is located outside of Canada it will be subject to the laws of the country in which it is situated.  
  
Notwithstanding our efforts, the Internet and online services have inherent security risks. The Great Courses cannot promise, and you should not expect, that your Personal Information, personal searches, and other communications will always remain secure. You should take care with regard to how you handle and disclose your Personal Information or any username or password that you are required to use to access services on the Website or online service.

**7.  Data Retention Periods**

We will retain your Personal Information as needed to provide you services and for our own records. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you Services contact us at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com). We will retain and use your Information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**8.  Keeping Your Information Updated**

We take care to keep the Personal Information in our records as accurate, complete and up to date as necessary for the purposes for which it is used. However, we also rely on you to tell us when your Personal Information changes. You may update and correct as necessary your personal information by contacting us using our contact information in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

**9\. Other Social Media Websites, Blogs, Message Boards**

The Website and The Great Courses Plus Mobile applications may make chat rooms, forums, commenting and message boards available to you and other users. You are not required to provide any Personal Information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. If you post Personal Information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. In addition, when you post a comment, the user name with which you registered for the Website and your current location may be made publicly available on the Website and through The Great Courses Plus Mobile applications. By using the commenting features of the Website and The Great Courses Plus Mobile applications, you acknowledge that your user name and location information will be disclosed. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose Personal Information in these areas. To request removal of your Personal Information from our Website, message boards or other community forums, contact us at: ContactUs@TheGreatCoursesPlus.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**10\.  General Audience Website Not Directed Toward Children**

This Website is a general audience Website. Our content is neither directed toward minors nor children who are under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If The Great Courses or our Internet Service Providers become aware that a minor or a child under the age of 13 has provided us with Personal Information without the parental consent, that information will be deleted from our databases. Parents who have questions about Personal Information that may have been submitted by a child under the age of 13 should email us at: [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:ContactUs@TheGreatCoursesPlus.com)

**11\.  Consent to Privacy Policy**

By using this Website or The Great Courses Plus Service, you signify your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy. We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post a notice on the Website and/or send an email to users who have provided an email address. Please note that you should always update your personal information to provide us with a current email address. 

**12\.  Access to Personal Information and Privacy Concerns**

You have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to have any concerns you may have over our policies and practices addressed. In addition, you have the right to obtain information regarding our policies and practices with respect to our use of service providers outside Canada. To access your information, discuss your concerns or learn more about our policies and practices please see our contact information in the “How to Contact Us” section below.  

**13\.  Questions About This Privacy Policy and How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the privacy practices of this Website, please contact us by email at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com).

You may also call us at 1-800-832-2412 or send a letter to:

The Great Courses

Attn: Customer Care    

4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400

Chantilly, VA, 20151-2299

**Effective Date: July 1, 2017, Revised June 8, 2021, Revised June 4, 2024**

**ca**

Welcome to The Great Courses Plus and to the thegreatcouresplus.com website (“Website”).   The Teaching Company Sales, LLC d/b/a The Great Courses ("The Great Courses", the "Company", "we" and "us"), its subsidiaries and affiliates value your participation and loyalty. We are committed to the protection of subscriber and customer privacy. The Great Courses has created this Privacy Notice in order to demonstrate its commitment to the privacy and protection of your Personal Information (as defined below). To better protect your privacy, The Great Courses provides this notice explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used in connection with our The Great Courses Plus service.

By using the Website, you confirm that you accept our Terms and Conditions and our use of Cookies as set out in our [Cookies Policy](https://www.wondrium.com/cookies), and that you have read and understood this Privacy Notice.  We may amend this Privacy Notice at any time.  If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or disclose your Personal Information, we will post a notice on the Website and/or send an email to users who have provided an email address.

**Information About Us**

Our service and Website are operated by The Teaching Company Sales, LLC, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, VA 20151-2299 (under the name of “The Great Courses”). You can contact us by sending an email to contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com.  “The Great Courses Plus” is the name of our subscription-based service.

**Privacy Officer**

Our Company Privacy Officer is our General Counsel, who can be reached at The Teaching Company Sales, LLC, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, Virginia 20151, Attn: General Counsel.  Our Privacy Officer can also be reached at legal@teachco.com.

**1\.  What Information Is Collected**

The following are the types of information we may collect:

**Personal Information**

The Great Courses may collect personal information (“Personal Information”), which includes any information relating to you or which can be used to identify you. This shall include but is not limited to, name, telephone number, email address, date of birth, home or business mailing address, IP address, and details regarding your mode of payment (_e.g._, credit/debit card or account information).

**Non-Personal Information**

At other times, The Great Courses may collect information that cannot be used to directly identify you (“Non-Personal Information” and, together with Personal Information, “Information”), such as browser type or “click stream” data. We may aggregate Non-Personal Information about you and other customers who visit certain areas of our Website. Aggregated information will not contain any information that can be linked directly back to you. If certain Non-Personal Information could identify you, when combined with the Personal Information you have given us, this will be considered Personal Information for the purposes of this Privacy Notice.

**Electronic Communications**

When you engage in email, SMS or MMS communications, we may log and store such information, as necessary, or for training and monitoring purposes.

We may also keep records of various communications regarding the types of products and services that you indicate are of interest to you via your response to email and text messaging.

You have the option to opt-out of our marketing communications when you complete your subscription check out process on the Website or by clicking “unsubscribe” in our emails or replying “STOP” to our text messages.

While we take all reasonable steps to protect the privacy of our Website visitors, we cannot promise that the current limitations of our online applications programming will address every browser setting or honor every personal browser preference. In particular, we have not implemented the necessary program changes to honor “Do Not Track” or “DNT” browser signals. As our online applications programming is refined, we will take all reasonable steps to honor such requests in the future. Please return to this Privacy Notice for further updates on this topic.

Our online service providers or business partners may implement technologies that allow for the collection of personally identifiable information over time and across third-party websites. We recommend that you review each privacy policy posted on the websites that you visit to better understand privacy practices on those websites.

**2\. How Do We Collect Information**

We may collect Information from you in several different areas on the Website, including, without limitation, those described below:

**Registration**

You will be asked to complete a registration form and provide Personal Information.  You will be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to access your subscription, as well as to take advantage of certain features on the Website or digital messaging services. You will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose Personal Information to us and what communications you would like to receive. Please be advised that access to certain products and services available on the Website require registration and if you elect not to provide such information, you will not be able to take advantage of those products and services.

**Contests Or Sweepstakes**

We may operate contests and sweepstakes through the Website and messaging services connected to contests and sweepstakes that will require registration or the submission of Personal Information. This Personal Information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes (see the rules of each contest for details about how your Personal Information will be used, including postings to the Website).

**Surveys And Games**

From time-to-time we may request Personal Information from you in conjunction with a survey or games, such as quizzes. Participation is voluntary, and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose Personal Information to the Website. At times, you may have to register to vote or to take part in a survey. When you register to play games on our Website, you may be asked to provide Personal Information.

**Transaction Information**

If you conduct a financial transaction on the Website, such as subscribing to The Great Courses Plus service or order other products/services offered on the Website, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain Personal Information from you, including contact information, demographic information, credit card and other financial information. Even though the collection form may have the look and feel of www.thegreatcoursesplus.com, please be aware you will be giving your Personal Information to our authorized payment processors (such as credit card service processors) and to third-party Internet Service Providers, and that in some instances the Privacy Policies of those third-party Internet Service Providers will govern the collection of your Personal Information. Please reference the privacy policies of such third-parties, as directed, for any privacy related concerns.

**Contacting Customer Care**

If you contact us by email, telephone or any other means to report a problem with the Website or our services, or you request information from us, we may record your Personal Information, as well as the content of your communication, for account management, training and monitoring purposes.  Calls may be recorded for training and monitoring purposes.

**Cookies and Tracking Technology**

We may use any number of tools to collect Personal Information about you, your computer access points, and the web browser that you use to connect to our Website. For example, “cookies” are tiny text files that we place on your computer’s hard drive when you visit our Website. We may use cookies as detailed in our [Cookies Policy](https://www.wondrium.com/cookies) to personalize your Website experience and improve our services.

The Great Courses may also collect additional Information from your web browser each time you visit our Website. This information may be anonymized/aggregated (Non-Personal Information) or may identify you when combined with the Personal Information you have given us. This information will include:

* Information about your visit, including the pages that you visit, “click stream” data to, through and from the Website (including date and time), products you viewed and searched for, length of visits to certain pages including video content, page response times, download errors, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), the promotions or advertisements that you click on, the courses you watch, and other actions that you take while using our Website; and
* Technical Information, including your login information, your IP address, the type of browser, the time that your browser was used to access our Website, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and the referring website address.

Our Internet Service Providers (defined below) and supporting service platform providers may also use other standard web-based technologies to analyze your movements while accessing our Website. The technologies may include analytic solutions, web “beacons,” “pixel tags,” and “clear gifs.” These technologies help us ascertain the effectiveness of our product and service campaigns and marketing programs, allow us to customize the services offered on or through our Website, and help determine the best use for Website content, and product and service offerings. Some of this information, including the IP address, may be stored on our Internet Service Provider’s server logs, and may be available for extended periods of time. Please see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.wondrium.com/cookies) for further details.

**3\.  How Your Information Is Used**

The Great Courses and its partners may use your Personal Information and/or Non-Personal Information for the following purposes:

* Confirm and enable your subscription;
* Carry out obligations arising from any contract entered into between you and us and to provide you with information, products and services;
* Determine your general geographic location and internet service provider to enable us to quickly and efficiently respond to inquiries and requests;
* Complete financial or other transactions that you have requested;
* Communicate with you about your account or transactions with us, including order confirmation from us or your designated payment processor;
* Send you information regarding changes to our policies;

* Personalize content and experiences on our Websites;
* Provide you with advertising based on your activity on our Websites and applications and on third-party sites and applications;
* Send you articles of interest on the subjects covered by our courses;
* Send you e-mail surveys to vote for the courses you want us to make, to rate the quality of our service or individual course titles, and to tell us what improvements to make to our services;

* Optimize or improve our products, services and operations;
* Detect, investigate and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal and

* Send you offers and promotions for The Great Courses products and services, or third-party products and services if you have specifically consented to this.

We may also use your IP address to help protect us and our Internet Service Providers from fraud. Additional uses of your Non-Personal and Personal Information will allow us to tailor products and services specific to your needs, to help organize and manage your customer relationship and our business, to conduct business, to provide you with customer and member support, to perform functions that are described to you at the time of collection, and to enforce our Website’s Terms of Use.

We may also use Non-Personal aggregate information to improve our Website. For example, our Internet Service Providers may report to us that there were a particular number of visitors to a certain area of our Website, or that a certain number of men or a certain number of women completed our registration form in particular areas of our Website. Such information may also be used to analyze the effectiveness of our business and advertising models.

**4\.  Shared Information**

The Great Courses uses the services of independent companies to provide certain services to you, including, without limitation, website hosting services, cloud hosting service providers (such as Amazon Web Services), course content distribution services, credit and debit card processing, mobile application providers, order fulfilment, contest and sweepstakes processing, and internet connectivity services (“Internet Service Providers”) in connection with The Great Courses.  We may share your Non-Personal and Personal Information with these third parties to the extent necessary to carry out obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.

We may work with Facebook, other social network sites, on-line marketing platforms and programmatic advertising services to display interest-based TTC ads to you in various on-line settings. We may share hashed/encrypted email addresses or phone numbers with these social media and on-line platforms to enable them to identify which users use our service.  If you do not want to receive interest-based ads on these sites, you can adjust your ad preferences through your settings on those sites.

We may also disclose your Personal Information as is necessary to:

1. comply with a subpoena or court order;
2. cooperate with law enforcement or other government agencies;
3. establish or exercise our legal rights;
4. protect the property or safety of our company and employees, contractors, vendors, and suppliers;
5. defend against legal claims;
6. help with internal and external investigations; or
7. as otherwise required by law or permitted by law.

We may disclose your information in connection with the sale or merger of The Great Courses or any transaction that involves the sale or assignment of some or all of our assets.

With your consent we use third-party ad serving, analytics, and audience and traffic measurement services.   We may use a third-party network advertiser to serve the advertisements on the Website or may use a traffic measurement service to analyze the traffic on the Website or the use of our Services. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to this Website and other Websites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products or Websites you might be interested in.  Audience and traffic measurement services allow us to collect anonymous traffic and behavior information from the Website by monitoring anonymous visitor activity. The Website's advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer with your consent. Cookies allow third-party advertisers to show you advertisements or content you might be interested in with your consent. Note that any images (or any other parts of a web page) served by third parties in association with third-party cookies may serve as web beacons, which enable third parties to carry out the previously described activities with your consent. Please see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.wondrium.com/cookies) for further details.  

With regard to name and postal address only, from time to time and if you have given consent, we may make our mailing list available to carefully screened companies. You have the option to withhold your consent when you complete your registration on the Website.  Thereafter, if you would like to withdraw your consent, please contacting us at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com), or write to us at The Great Courses, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, VA, 20151-2299, Attn: Customer Care or by contacting the third party who has contacted you.

**5\.  Links To Third-party Websites**

Links from this Website may allow you to directly access websites operated by third parties, including, without limitation, our service providers or marketing partners. The privacy policies of these third-party websites may differ from ours. These websites may ask you for Personal Information. Please review the privacy policy on third-party websites before submitting information, because we do not have control over the use of information collected on these websites.  

You may be able to access this Website or your The Great Courses Plus subscription content through third parties with whom we have marketing relationships.  Some of these third-party marketing channels may be “co-branded” with our logo; however, note that these third-party channels are not operated, controlled or maintained by The Great Courses. These channels or links are provided for your convenience only and should be used with your discretion and prudent judgment. Links from our Website to third-party websites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement, or approval of the content, policies or practices of such third-party websites. The collection and use of your information by such co-branded third party is the responsibility of the co-branding partner, and they may use your personal information for their direct marketing purposes.  We are not responsible for any information these websites or digital channels may obtain and we do not oversee their policies or practices. This Privacy Notice does not apply to information provided to or gathered by the third parties that operate them.

**6\.  Information Security And Storage**

Information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or a third party. This includes staff engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services as listed elsewhere in this Privacy Notice. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your Information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

The Great Courses makes reasonable efforts to ensure that our Internet Service Providers, and any other person to whom we disclose your Personal Information to, have implemented appropriate physical, electronic, and procedural security measures to assist with safeguarding your Personal Information, and to help protect against unauthorized access and disclosure. We use contracts and other measures with our service providers to maintain the confidentiality and security of your Personal Information and to prevent such Personal Information from being used for any other purpose.        

Notwithstanding our efforts, the Internet and online services have inherent security risks. The Great Courses cannot promise, and you should not expect, that your Personal Information, personal searches, and other communications will always remain secure. You should take care with regard to how you handle and disclose your Personal Information or any username or password that you are required to use to access services on the Website or online service.

**7\.  Deleting The Information We Hold About You**

We will retain your Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. You have the right to cancel your account or to request that we delete (or restrict the use of) any, or all, of the Information we hold about you, unless we need to retain your Information as necessary e.g. in order to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. If you would like us to delete your Information, please contact us at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)

We may restrict or block the processing of your request to delete Information in the following circumstances:

1. where you have made a request that your Information be deleted or you have questioned the accuracy of your Information, and your request is being verified; or
2. where we need to retain the data to comply with law, regulation, internal audit requirements, or to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim.

**8\. Accessing Your Information**

You have the right to know what Information we hold about you and its source, the categories of the Information, whether it is shared with third parties, whether it has been sent outside the EEA and if so what safeguards are in place, how we use your Information, the purpose of that use and, where possible, the period for which your Information will be stored.

You are entitled to a copy of all the Information we hold on you.  This request should be made to [ContactUs@thegreatcouresplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com). We will respond to the extent reasonably possible and in accordance with applicable law.

**9\. Your Right to Rectification**

We take care to keep Personal Information in our records as accurate, complete and up to date as necessary for the purposes for which it is used. However, we also rely on you to tell us when your Personal Information changes. If you believe we hold inaccurate or incomplete Information about you, please contact us at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com).

10. **Other Social Media Websites, Blogs, Message Boards**

The Website and The Great Courses Plus Mobile applications may make chat rooms, forums, commenting and message boards available to you and other users. You are not required to provide any Personal Information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. If you post Personal Information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. In addition, when you post a comment, the user name with which you registered for the Website and your current location may be made publicly available on the Website and through The Great Courses Plus Mobile applications. By using the commenting features of the Website and The Great Courses Plus Mobile applications, you acknowledge that your user name and location information will be disclosed. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose Personal Information in these areas. To request removal of your Personal Information from our message boards or other community forums, contact us at: [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

12. **General Audience Website Not Directed Toward Children**

This Website is a general audience Website. Our content is neither directed toward minors nor children who are under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If The Great Courses or our Internet Service Providers become aware that a minor or a child under the age of 13 has provided us with Personal Information without the parental consent, that information will be deleted from our databases. Parents who have questions about Personal Information that may have been submitted by a child under the age of 13 should email us at: [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)

13. **Consent to Privacy Notice**

By using this Website or The Great Courses Plus Service, you signify that you have read and agree with the terms of this Privacy Notice. When you register withThe Great Courses Plus, you will be asked to consent to certain uses of your Personal Information. You have the right to withdraw this consent at any time by contacting us at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com). We may amend this Privacy Notice at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your Personal Information, we will post a notice on the Website and/or send an email to users who have provided an email address. Please note that you should always update your Personal Information and provide us with a current email address. 

13. **Questions About This Privacy Notice**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice or the privacy practices of this Website, please contact us by email at [ContactUs@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com).

You may also send a letter to:

The Great Courses

Attn: Customer Care    

4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400

Chantilly, VA, 20151-2299

**Effective Date:  May 2017, Revised June 8, 2021, Revised June 4, 2024**

**gb**

Welcome to The Great Courses Plus and to thegreatcoursesplus.com Website (“Website”).   The Teaching Company Sales, LLC d/b/a The Great Courses ("The Great Courses"), its subsidiaries and affiliates, or other members of our family of companies value your participation and loyalty. We are committed to the protection of subscriber, customer and community privacy. The Great Courses has created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate its commitment to the privacy and protection of your personal information. To better protect your privacy, The Great Courses provides this notice explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used in connection with our The Great Courses service.

By using the Website, you confirm that you accept our Terms and Conditions and our use of Cookies as set out in our [Cookies Policy](https://www.wondrium.com/cookies), and that you have read and understood this Privacy Notice.  We may amend this Privacy Notice at any time.  If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or disclose your Personal Information, we will post a notice on the Website and/or send an email to users who have provided an email address.

**Information about Us**

Our Service and Website is operated by The Teaching Company Sales, LLC, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, VA 20151-2299 (under the name of “The Great Courses”). If you would like information on how to contact us, click Contact Us.   “The Great Courses Plus” is the name of our subscription-based service.

**1\. What Information Is Collected**

The following are the types of information we may collect:

**Personal Information**

The Great Courses may collect personal information, which shall include but is not limited to, name, telephone number, email address, date of birth, home or business mailing address, and details regarding your mode of payment, _e.g._, credit/debit card or account information, when you access certain areas of the Website that require registration or payment for products and services, or if you require more information about those services.  
  
**Non-Personal Information**  
At other times, The Great Courses may collect information that cannot be used to directly identify you, such as browser type, Dynamic Internet Protocol (IP) address, “click stream” data, and similar non-personally identifiable information.  For example, we may aggregate non-personal information about you and other customers who visit certain areas of our Website. Aggregated information will not contain any information that can be linked directly back to you.  
  
While we take all reasonable steps to protect the privacy of our Website visitors, we cannot promise that the current limitations of our online applications programming will address every browser setting or honor every personal browser preference. In particular, we have not implemented the necessary program changes to honor “Do Not Track” or “DNT” browser signals. As our online applications programming is refined, we will take all reasonable steps to honor such requests in the future. Please return to this Privacy Policy for further updates on this topic.  
  
Further, our online service providers or business partners may implement technologies that allow for the collection of personally identifiable information over time and across Websites. We recommend that you review each privacy policy posted on the Websites that you visit to better understand privacy practices on those Websites.  
  
**Electronic Communications**  
When you open emails from us or engage in SMS or MMS communications, we may log and store such information. We may also keep records of various communications regarding the types of products and services that you indicate are of interest to you via your response to email and text messaging. You will always have the option to opt-out of such communications by clicking an “unsubscribe” link or replying “STOP” to our text messages.  
  
**  
2\. How Do We Collect Information**  
We may collect information from you in several different areas on the Website, including, without limitation, those described below:  
  
**Registration**  
You will be asked to complete a registration form and provide personally identifiable information.  You will be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to access your subscription, as well as to take advantage of certain features on the Website or digital messaging services, such as newsletters or contests. You will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to us and what communications you would like to receive; however, please be advised that many products and services available on the Website require registration and if you elect not to provide such information, you will not be able to take advantage of those products and services.  
  
**Contests or Sweepstakes**  
We periodically operate contests and sweepstakes through the Website and messaging services that will require registration or the submission of personal information. Your personally identifiable information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes (see the rules of each contest for details about how your personal information will be used, including postings to the Website).  
  
**Surveys and Games**  
From time-to-time we may request personally identifiable information from you in conjunction with a survey or games, such as quizzes. Participation is voluntary, and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. At times, you may have to register to vote or to take part in a survey. When you register to play games on our Website, you may be asked to provide personally identifiable information.  
  
**Cookies and Tracking Technology**  
We may use any number of tools to collect information about you, your computer access points, and the web browser that you use to connect to our Website. For example, “cookies” are tiny text files that we place on your computer’s hard drive when you visit our Website. We may use cookies to personalize your Website experience. You do not have to accept our cookies and you may delete them after they have been placed on your hard drive. If you do not accept or delete our cookies, some areas of our Website that you access may take more time to work, or may not function properly. For more information about cookies, visit: [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).  
  
The Great Courses may also collect additional information from your web browser each time you visit our Website. We may collect information on the pages that you visit, the promotions or advertisements that you click on, the courses you watch, and other actions that you take while using our Website. This information may include your IP address, the type of browser, the time that your browser was used to access our Website, and the referring Website address.  
  
Our Internet Service Providers (defined below) and supporting service platform providers may also use other standard web-based technologies to analyze your movements while accessing our Website. The technologies may include analytic solutions, web “beacons,” “pixel tags,” and “clear gifs.” These technologies help us ascertain the effectiveness of our product and service campaigns and marketing programs, allow us to customize the services offered on or through our Website, and help determine the best use for Website content, and product and service offerings. Some of this information, including the IP address, may be stored on our Internet service provider’s server logs, and may be available for extended periods of time.  
  
**Transaction Information**  
If you conduct a financial or other transaction with or on the Website, such as subscribe to The Great Courses or order other products/services offered on the Website, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain information from you, including contact information, demographic information, credit card and/or other financial information. Even though the collection form may have the look and feel of thegreatcoursesplus.com, please be aware you will be giving your information to our and your authorized payment processors (such as credit card service processors or Amazon Payments) and to third party Internet Service Providers, and that in some instances the Privacy Policies of those third party Internet Service Providers will govern the collection of your personal information. Please reference the privacy policies available from these pages for any privacy related concerns.  
  
We and/or our Internet Service Providers will use this information to complete the financial or other transaction that you have requested, _i.e.,_ to deliver the information, products or other services that you request or purchase, to invoice you, and in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy. For your protection, financial information is collected and stored through encrypted means.  
  
**3\. How Is your Information Used**  
The Great Courses and its partners may use your personal information and/or non-personally identifiable information for the following purposes:

* Provide you with The Great Courses products and services
* Communicate with you about your account or transactions with us and send you information about features on our Website and applications or changes to our policies
* Send you offers and promotions for The Great Courses products and services or third-party products and services 
* Personalize content and experiences on our Websites and applications
* Provide you with advertising based on your activity on our Websites and applications and on third-party sites and applications.
* Optimize or improve our products, services and operations
* Detect, investigate and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal

 The Great Courses uses the services of independent companies to provide certain services to you, including, without limitation, Website hosting services, course content distribution services, credit and debit card processing, mobile application providers, order fulfillment, contest and sweepstakes processing, and Internet connectivity services (“Internet Service Providers”) in connection with The Great Courses.  We may share your non-personal and personal information with these third parties as necessary to provide these services to you.  
  
We use your personal information to send you order confirmations. In such cases, you should receive via e-mail an order confirmation after placing your order.  You may also receive confirmation e-mails from your designated payment processor.  Occasionally, you will receive articles of interest on the subjects covered by our courses. From time-to-time you may receive e-mail surveys to vote for The Great Courses you want us to make, to rate the quality of The Great Courses Service or individual course titles, and to tell us what improvements to make to The Great Courses and our services. We may also use your personal information to notify you of special offers. You may receive e-mails notifying you when individual courses featured in our print catalogs and newsletters go on sale. These e-mails also make ordering extremely simple—if you see courses that interest you, simply click on the links in the e-mail to find out more.  
  
We may also use your IP address to help protect us and our Internet Service Providers from fraud. Additional uses of your non-personal and personal information will allow us to tailor products and services specific to your needs, to help organize and manage your customer relationship and our business, to conduct business, to provide you with customer and member support, to perform functions that are described to you at the time of collection, and to enforce our Website’s Terms of Use.  
  
We may also use non-personal aggregate information to improve our Website. For example, our Internet Service Providers may report to us that there were a particular number of visitors to a certain area of our Website, or that a certain number of men or a certain number of women completed our registration form in particular areas of our Website. Such information may also be used to analyze the effectiveness of our business and advertising models.  
  
**4\. Shared Information**  
We may share your personal information with the Internet Service Providers as appropriate.  We may also share personally identifiable information with outside, non-affiliated third parties that offer products and services that are complementary to our product lines. We may also disclose your personal information as is necessary to: (a) comply with a subpoena or court order; (b) cooperate with law enforcement or other government agency; (c) establish or exercise our legal rights; (d) protect the property or safety of our company and employees, contractors, vendors, and suppliers; (e) defend against legal claims; (f) help with internal and external investigations; or (g) as otherwise required by law or permitted by law. We may disclose your information in connection with the sale or merger of The Great Courses or any transaction that involves the sale or assignment of some or all of our assets.  
  
We use third-party ad serving, analytics, and audience and traffic measurement services.   We may use a third-party network advertiser to serve the advertisements on the Website or may use a traffic measurement service to analyze the traffic on the Website or the use of our Services. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to this Website and other Websites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products or Websites you might be interested in.  Audience and traffic measurement services allow us to collect anonymous traffic and behavior information from the Website by monitoring anonymous visitor activity. Although advertisers or other companies do not have access to the Website cookies, the Website's advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer if you choose to have your cookies enabled in your browser. Cookies allow third-party advertisers to show you advertisements or content you might be interested in. Note that any images (or any other parts of a web page) served by third parties in association with third-party cookies may serve as web beacons, which enable third parties to carry out the previously described activities. Other companies' uses of their cookies are subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Please visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout\_nonppii.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp) in order to learn more about the information collection practices and "opt-out" procedures of third-party ad servers we may use. We utilize the analysis services of Crazy Egg on our Website, click [here](https://www.crazyegg.com/privacy) to view its privacy policy and [here](https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out) to view its opt out feature. Additionally, Crazy Egg [terms and conditions](https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out) regarding your activity and content on this Website, its disclaimer of liability, arbitration and dispute resolution apply to this Website, and Crazy Egg is a third party beneficiary of such provisions.  
  
With regard to name and postal address only, from time to time, we may make our mailing list available to carefully screened companies. If you prefer we don’t share your name and postal address, please call our Customer Care team at 1-800-832-2412 or write to us at The Great Courses, 4840 Westfields Blvd., Suite 400, Chantilly, VA, 20151-2299, Attn: Customer Care.  
  
**5\. Links To Third-party Websites**  
Links from this Website may allow you to directly access Websites operated by third parties, including, without limitation, our service providers or marketing partners. And, you may be able to access this Website or your The Great Courses subscription content through third parties with whom we have marketing relationships.  Some of these third-party marketing channels may be “co-branded” with our logo; however, note that  these third-party channels are not operated, controlled or maintained by The Great Courses. These channels or links are provided for your convenience only and should be used with your discretion and prudent judgment. Links from our Website to third-party Websites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement, or approval of the content, policies or practices of such third-party Websites. The collection and use of your information by such co-branding third parties is the responsibility of the co-branding partner, and they may use your personal information for their direct marketing purposes.  We are not responsible for any information these Websites or digital channels may obtain and we do not oversee their policies or practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information provided to or gathered by the third parties that operate them. The privacy policies of these third-party Websites may differ from ours. These Websites may ask you for Personal Information. Please review the privacy policy on third-party channels before submitting information, because we do not have control over the use of information collected on these Websites. Please review the privacy policies and practices of these digital channels before providing any Personal Information.  
  
**6\. Information Security**  
The Great Courses makes reasonable efforts to ensure that our Internet Service Providers have implemented physical, electronic, and procedural security measures to assist with safeguarding your personal information, and to help protect against unauthorized access and disclosure. Only our authorized personnel and our Internet Service Providers who perform legitimate business functions for The Great Courses are authorized to access your personal information.  
  
Notwithstanding our efforts, the Internet and online services have inherent security risks.  The Great Courses cannot promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information, personal searches, and other communications will always remain secure. You should take care with regard to how you handle and disclose your personal information or any username or password that you are required to use to access services on this Website or online service.  
  
**7\. Data Retention Periods**  
We will retain your personally identifiable information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.  
  
**8\. Other Social Media Websites, Blogs, Message Boards**  
The Website and The Great Courses Mobile applications may make chat rooms, forums, commenting and message boards available to you and other users. You are not required to provide any personal information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. If you post personal information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. In addition, when you post a comment, the user name with which you registered for the Website and your current location may be made publicly available on the Website and through The Great Courses Mobile applications. By using the commenting features of the Website and The Great Courses Mobile applications, you acknowledge that your user name and location information will be disclosed. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in these areas. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at: [contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.  
  
**9\. General Audience Website Not Directed Toward Children**  
This Website is a general audience Website. Our content is neither directed toward minors nor children who are under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If The Great Courses or our Internet Service Providers become aware that a minor or a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personal information without the parental consent, that information will be deleted from our databases. Parents who have questions about personal information that may have been submitted by a child under the age of 13 should email us at: [contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:ContactUs@TheGreatCoursesPlus.com)  
  
**10\. Consent to Privacy Policy**  
By using this Website or The Great Courses, you signify your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy. We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post a notice on the Website and/or send an email to users who have provided an email address. Please note that you should always update your personal information to provide us with a current email address.  
  
**11\. Access to Personal Information and Consent to Transfer**  
The first time that you provide us with registration information through our Website, you may be offered the opportunity to subscribe to and receive additional information about our products and services. After your first use, you can make changes to your personal information and your initial choices by accessing your account or by contacting customer service e-mail at [contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com).  
  
The United States may not have data privacy laws that are deemed to afford an equal level of protection for your Personal Information as those laws legislated at the direction of the European Union or similar geopolitical, national or regional legislative bodies. However, please be assured that The Great Courses will continue to adhere to the principles stated in this Privacy Policy and will make reasonable efforts to comply with applicable international, national, regional, territorial, and provincial laws in connection with any information collected through the Website. The Great Courses will endeavor to preserve the integrity, confidentiality, and security of personal information and afford such personal information reasonable level of protection.  
  
For those Website users located outside the United States, we advise you that your information may at times be accessible by individuals who are located worldwide including in countries that the European Commission or other geopolitical regions have not been determined to provide the same level of data protection as in your country, province, territory or geopolitical region. By providing us with your Personal Information, you consent to our use of it in accordance with The Great Courses Privacy Policy, including the transfer of your information across international boundaries to jurisdictions anywhere in the world as permitted by local law.  
  
**12\. Questions About This Privacy Policy**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the privacy practices of this Website, please contact us by email at [contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:contactus@thegreatcoursesplus.com)[](mailto:customerservice@thegreatcoursesplus.com).

**PRIVACY POLICY ADDENDUM FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS**

Under the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”), California residents are afforded certain rights regarding the personal information  The Great Courses (“we”, “our”, “us”) collect about them.  California residents may request any of the following: 

* The categories of information that we collected.
* The categories of sources from which the information is collected.
* The purpose for collecting information.
* The categories of third parties to whom we disclosed information, the categories of such information that was disclosed (if applicable), and the purpose for disclosing information.
* The specific pieces of information we collected.

You may also request the deletion of information we have collected, as well as the right to opt-out of the sale of your personal information. 

Consistent with the California Consumer Protection Act, we will consider and timely process data access and deletion requests. We will not unlawfully discriminate against you for making any such requests.  To initiate access or deletion requests, you can contact us at [Calprivacy@thegreatcoursesplus.com](mailto:Calprivacy@thegreatcoursesplus.com).

**SALES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We allow companies to use cookies and other tracking technologies on our sites that allow those companies to collect information about your website activity and use that information to target advertisements to you online.  You can exercise control over the use of these technologies.  _See_ the [Cookies Policy](https://www.wondrium.com/cookies)**.**  In addition, to opt-out of the “sale” of personal information, you can click here:  [Do Not Sell My Personal Information](https://www.wondrium.com/ccpa).

**HOW WE COLLECT AND SHARE CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS’ INFORMATION**

Over the last 12 months, personal information we have collected and shared includes the following:

| Categories of Information | Sources of Information | Uses of Information | Sharing of Information |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Identifiers, including name, telephone number, email address, birthdate, home or business mailing address, IP address, demographic information credit card and account information, and username and password if you register. | We collect this information directly from you when you register, complete surveys, enter contests or sweepstakes, transact business with us, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and automatically when you visit the Website, and  from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To confirm purchases, deliver products and services, determine your location, communicate with you, send articles of interest to you, send email surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services or third parties’ products and services, improve our products and services, detect and investigate incidents and protect against fraud, analysis of the Website traffic. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfilment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Personal information as defined by Cal. Civ. Code 1798.80, including name, telephone number, email address, birthdate, home or business mailing address, IP address, demographic information credit card and account information, and username and password if you register. | We collect this information directly from you when you register, complete surveys, enter contests or sweepstakes, transact business with us, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and automatically when you visit the Website, and  from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To confirm purchases, deliver products and services, determine your location, communicate with you, send articles of interest to you, send email surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services or third parties’ products and services, improve our products and services, detect and investigate incidents and protect against fraud, analysis of the Website traffic. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfilment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Characteristics of protected classifications, including race, color, religion/creed, national origin or ancestry, sex, gender, age, physical/mental disability, veteran status, genetic information, citizenship, occupation, marital status, income and/or employment status. | We may collect this information directly from you when you complete surveys or register for information, products and services. | To market, sell, and improve our products and services, send you surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services, send articles of interest to you. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfilment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Commercial information including information on your purchases, mode of payment (e.g. credit/debit card purchases), products and services you show interest in, your marketing preferences, survey responses, electronic communications. | We collect this information directly from you when you register, complete surveys, enter contests or sweepstakes, transact business with us, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and automatically when you visit the Website, and  from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To confirm purchases, deliver products and services, determine your location, communicate with you, send articles of interest to you, send email surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services or third parties’ products and services, improve our products and services, detect and investigate incidents and protect against fraud, analysis of the Website traffic. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfilment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Internet or other electronic network activity information including, information about your visit, including information collected through the use of cookies, website  pages visited, “click stream” data, promotions you click on, courses watched, your Website movement, and other actions you take while using our Website, technical information, browser type, the time that your browser was used to access our Website, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and the referring website address. | We collect this information directly from you when you register, complete surveys, enter contests or sweepstakes, transact business with us, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and automatically when you visit the Website, and  from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To confirm purchases, deliver products and services, determine your location, communicate with you, send articles of interest to you, send email surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services or third parties’ products and services, improve our products and services, detect and investigate incidents and protect against fraud, analysis of the Website traffic | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfillment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory or similar information, including your customer support calls (which may be recorded for training purposes). | We collect this information directly from you when you register, transact business with us,, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and automatically when you visit the Website, and  from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To confirm purchases, deliver products and services, determine your location, communicate with you, send articles of interest to you, send email surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services or third parties’ products and services, improve our products and services, detect and investigate incidents and protect against fraud, analysis of the Website traffic. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfillment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Professional and employment related information such as your occupation, and/or your professional status. | We collect this information directly from you when you register, complete surveys, enter contests or sweepstakes, transact business with us, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To market, sell, and improve our products and services, send you surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services, send articles of interest to you. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfillment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Educational information, such as education level attained, degrees attained, and schools attended, may be collected. | We collect this information directly from you when you complete surveys, or enter contests or sweepstakes, contact customer care, or communicate with us, and from third parties who are our business partners and service providers. | To market, sell, and improve our products and services, send you surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services, send articles of interest to you. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfillment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |
| Inferences derived from personal information, including your purchasing habits and patterns, your purchasing and product preferences. | This information is derived from categories of information collected. | To market, sell, and improve our products and services, send you surveys, send offers and promotions for our products and services, send articles of interest to you. | Information may be shared with third party service providers for a business purpose, such as web hosting, cloud hosting, course content distribution services, credit/debit card processing, order fulfillment, internet connectivity, to carry out contractual obligations between you and us, to comply with legal processes and claims, for a sale or merger, and to  receive analysis of the Website audience and web traffic measurements, social media and online marketing platforms to display interest based ads. |

**Effective Date: November 1, 2019 - US, Revised January 1, 2020, Revised June 8, 2021, Revised May 5, 2022, Revised June 4, 2024**

Discover More [All Programs](https://www.wondrium.com/allprograms?CFM=footer)[My Purchases](https://www.wondrium.com/customer/account/purchases?CFM=footer) [Apps](https://www.wondrium.com/apps?CFM=footer) [TGC Journeys](https://www.thegreatcoursesjourneys.com/?utm_source=Plus&utm_medium=Web&utm_campaign=6000) [About Us](https://www.wondrium.com/about-us?CFM=footer) [Careers](https://recruiting.ultipro.com/TEA1007/JobBoard/12b1eb65-0740-4bd4-8d28-674cb5059f65/?q=&o=postedDateDesc) [Affiliates](https://www.wondrium.com/affiliates?CFM=footer&type=dm)

Help

Enjoy Anywhere! Access The Great Courses Plus anytime, on your TV,  
computer, or your favorite mobile device.

Connect With Us Choose your favorite way to follow us to get our latest deals, news, and information.

© The Teaching Company Sales, LLC. All rights reserved.

Discover More [All Programs](https://www.wondrium.com/allprograms?CFM=footer)[My Purchases](https://www.wondrium.com/customer/account/purchases?CFM=footer) [Apps](https://www.wondrium.com/apps?CFM=footer) [TGC Journeys](https://www.thegreatcoursesjourneys.com/?utm_source=Plus&utm_medium=Web&utm_campaign=6000) [About Us](https://www.wondrium.com/about-us?CFM=footer)[Careers](https://recruiting.ultipro.com/TEA1007/JobBoard/12b1eb65-0740-4bd4-8d28-674cb5059f65/?q=&o=postedDateDesc) [Affiliates](https://www.wondrium.com/affiliates?CFM=footer&type=dm)

Help

Enjoy Anywhere! Access The Great Courses Plus anytime, on your TV,  
computer, or your favorite mobile device.

Connect With Us Choose your favorite way to follow us to get our latest deals, news, and information.

Gifting Options

© The Teaching Company Sales, LLC. All rights reserved.

New Password Required

We've updated our website and apps to improve your Great Courses Plus experience.

This upgrade requires that you change your password. We've sent a link and instructions to **your email address** to help you easily reset your password and start exploring the new Great Courses Plus immediately.

OK. I understand.

This program is restricted from being viewed in your country. This is due to restrictions from the creator of the program.

Please choose another of our wide variety of programs to enjoy!

Ok

#### 

Link your Great Courses account with The Great Courses Plus.

Unlock a more convenient way to stream your entire course library.

1\. Sign in to The Great Courses.

2\. Sign in to The Great Courses Plus.

3\. Accounts Successfully linked!

#### Sign in to your Great Courses account.

 SHOW

Sign in

#### Create your Great Courses Plus account

Email

Email

 Remember me

Password

 SHOW _Password must be at least 6 characters_

 Create Account & Continue

Have an account? [Go back to sign in](#)

Stream your linked content​

Your accounts with The Great Courses and The Great Courses Plus are now linked together. ​  
Going forward, you can login to The Great Courses Plus to access your purchased content and your subscription all in one place. ​  
  
 You can un-link these accounts at any time in [My Account](https://www.wondrium.com/customer/account/)

#### Sign in to your Great Courses Plus (formerly Wondrium) account.

 Remember me

 SHOW

Sign in

#### Don’t have a Great Courses Plus Account?

Create account manually

OR

Use Great Courses Credentials

to create an account

By sharing your email address, you agree to our [Terms of Service](https://www.thegreatcoursesplus.com/tos/) and [Privacy Policy](https://www.thegreatcoursesplus.com/privacy/) and that you are 18 years of age or older.
